I like blue, purple
أحب الأزرق، البنفسجي،
and flowery patterns
المُزَهَّر.
Black -- not so much
الأسود - لا.
People say that it make you look skinny
يقولون أنه يُنَحِّف،
but it's gloomy
لكنه بائس
and I'm a colorful person
وأنا شخص يحبّ الألوان.
Originally, I'm from Petah Tikva
بالأصل، أنا من بيتَح تيكفا.
When I was 18
بسن 18،
I moved to Jerusalem
انتقلت إلى القدس.
That's where I met my husband
هناك تعرفت على زوجي.
On our first date
في موعدنا العاطفي الأول،
we had dinner at my place
أعددت عشاءًا في شقتي،
I told him that I love him
أخبرته بأنني أحبّه،
then we went to the movies
وبعدها ذهبنا لمشاهدة فيلم.
Today
واليوم،
we are 14 years together
نحن معًا 14 عامًا.
I had all sorts of periods in my life
كانت لدي فترات مختلفة،
People thought
وظنّ الناس،
that I won't be able to overcome
أنني لن أتمكن من التغلّب على ما أمرّه،
That I won't be able to be functional again
وأن أعود للعمل وأداء مهامي.
Since then I studied psychology and rhythmics
منذ ذاك الحين، درست علم النفس والانسجام الحركي،
Today I'm an assistant in the kindergarten
واليوم أنا أيضًا مساعدة في روضة،
and rehabilitative instructor
ومرشدة إعادة تأهيل،
I was afraid of working
في البداية كنت أخشى أن أعمل في أمكنة
in the same places where I was hospitalized before
التي مكثت فيها لتلقي العلاج،
But I was actually okay about it in the end
لكن ذلك لم يمسّني، كنت على ما يرام.
The stigma about people
الوصمة على أشخاص
with mental health issues
مع مشاكل نفسية
is that they are more violent
أنهم أكثر عنفًا.
This is simply not true
وهذا، بكل بساطة، غير صحيح.
It's important to understand that
ومن المهم إدراك
the illness is part of me
أن المرض هو جزء مني
but it is not who I am
لكته ليس أنا.
I hate the word "regular"
أكره كلمة "عادي"
People who cope with mental illnesses
أيضًا من يواجه (مرض نفسي)
are also regular
هم أشخاص عاديون
Everyone copes with something
وكلٌ منّا يواجه أمرًا ما.
Since the age of 12
منذ أن كنت في الـ12 من عمري،
I write poems
أكتب الأشعار.
I started by writing about friendship
في البداية عن الطفولة والصداقة،
and how hard it is for me
وحول كم أشعر بصعوبات.
"friendships are key
"الصداقة هي لي،
but sadly I don't have any
لكن للأسف، ليس لدي
I want it so badly
أريدها بشدّة،
but it's not a must"
لكن ليس بالضرورة أن تتحقق"
This is the first verse
هذا البيت الأول
of my first poem
من أول قصيدة كتبتها.
since then I continued writing
واصلت منذ ذاك الحين.
On the first anniversary of our wedding
في يوم زواجنا،
my husband gifted me a guitar
زوجي جلب لي جيثارة
Since then, our friends compose melodies for my poems
ومنذ ذاك الحين، يُلحّن أصدقائي الأشعار
and I play and sing
وأنا أعزف وأغني.
When people look at me
عندما ينظر الناس إليّ،
they think I'm too good
يظنون أنني طيّبة أكثر مما يجب.
I have a face
لدي وجه كمن
that expresses goodness
يشعّ خيرًا.
That wants to help
يريد المساعدة.
When we create eye contact
وعندما يقع تواصل بالعيون،
a connection is formed
يتكوّن رابط.